SERGEY RADKOV

6224 N. Park Meadow Way, Apt. 101, Boise ID 83713 • (208) 283-9080 • <u>radkovsn@gmail.com</u> *Permanent Work Authorization • No Visa Sponsorship Required • Open to Relocation*

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior Web developer with a passion for online businesses has extensive analysis knowledge and much experience of creating logical and innovative solutions to complex problems to increase efficiency, with 5+ years' telematics service promotion and 8 years' vehicle fleet management experience.

KEY SKILLS

- Practical and creative problem solver with exceptional attention to detail
- Strong presentation, communication and negotiation skills
- Demonstrated success in project and staff management
- Ability to work under pressure, meet tight deadlines and adapt to rapidly changing environments
- International experience and bi-lingual in English and Russian

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Java
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, AngularJS, jQuery, Express, NodeJS, Npm, Bower
- IDE/Editors: Microsoft Visual Code, IntelliJ IDEA

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive Full Stack Course

BoiseCodeWorks, Boise, Idaho

04/2016 - 06/2016

The leading premier coding bootcamp in Idaho.

The Immersive Course is a full-time experience designed for studding both front-end and back-end technologies, worked in groups under the supervision of experienced mentors to create fully functional real-world applications.

Master's Degree, Transport Management

(combined bachelor/master program)

09/1997 - 06/2002

State University of Management, Moscow, Russia

Russia's leading university in the field of management education

Five year program specialized in management, technology, communications and accounting for motor transport companies and business transport departments

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Engineer

Volvo Truck Russia, Moscow, Russia

07/2010 - 10/2015

A branch of Sweden-based Volvo Trucks, a global manufacturer with operations in over 140 countries

- Promoted Volvo telematics services, provided technical support for 600+ customers and 100+ team members
- Established new consulting service using Volvo's telematics data to design driving improvements that reduced customer fuel costs by up to 15%
- Increased truck telematics services by 2900% (200 to 6000) over 5 years
- Prepared and delivered technical presentations for existing and prospective customers and prepared and edited all telematics-related print and online materials
- Attended professional development trainings (presentation skills and time, conflict, and project management)

Transportation Coordinator

TOTAL Exploration & Production Russia, Moscow, Russia

02/2008 - 06/2010

Subsidiary of TOTAL S.A., a French multinational oil and gas company

- Managed company carpool of 120+ cars, managed 15 drivers, and oversaw staff/customer transportation services
- Ensured staff compliance with administrative policies and procedures, safety rules, union contracts, environmental policies and government regulations
- Oversaw contract compliance with leasing, insurance, transportation and other corporate partners
- Purchased company cars and ensured timely maintenance, resulting in cost savings of over 10%

Transportation Manager

Unimilk, Moscow, Russia

10/2006 - 08/2007

Russia's largest dairy producer; now owned by Danone, a world leader in the food industry

- Managed corporate carpool of 100+ cars, supervised 10+ drivers, and oversaw transportation services for staff and visitors
- Developed transportation plans, policies and budgets
- Oversaw contract compliance with leasing, insurance, transportation and other corporate partners
- Purchased company cars and ensured timely maintenance of all vehicles

Transportation Specialist

PKD Optima, Moscow, Russia

09/2003 - 10/2006

General distributor of Philip Morris USA in Russia

- Monitored transport department's safety, personal responsibility and maintenance policy compliance in ~20 company branches, with a total fleet of over 2000 vehicles
- Established each branch's transport department budgets and ensured compliance
- Oversaw purchase of company trucks and cars, with a yearly turnover more than 500 vehicles
- Negotiated contracts with insurance companies and oversaw compliance